本字幕由TLF翻译YYeTs人人影视合并双语
更多字幕 影视 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
很久以前  在古代中国
Long ago, a mythic battle between good and evil
发生了一场神话般的正邪之战
played out in ancient China.
内战的战火席卷了整个国家
The country was torn by civil war,
各诸侯国为了土地和权力征战不断
with many kingdoms struggling for land and power.
其中有一个王更野心勃勃 想要通过武力一统天下成为皇帝
But one king had a ruthless ambition to make himself emperor by the sword.
我要把它连成万里  连一个…
都退下
Leave me.
准备开战!
Prepare for war!
其他诸侯国唯恐被他吞并
NARRATOR... The other rulers hired assassins to kill the King
派出杀手刺杀他
before he could conquer them all.
不用!朕没事
Stop! I am not harmed.
今晚进攻!
We attack tonight!
他的军队一路战胜了一个又一个诸侯国
NARRATOR... Kingdom by kingdom, his army swept away everything in its path,
胆敢违抗他的人都没好下场
and anyone who resisted met a terrible fate.
最后整个国家都是他的
The country was his.
他成了一切万物的统治者
He was now Emperor of All Under Heaven.
战败的敌人都成了他的奴隶 为他建造万里长城
He enslaved his conquered enemies and forced them to build his Great Wall.
一旦他们死了或病了  就直接掩埋在城墙下
When they were dead or useless, he had them buried beneath it.
方士教会了皇帝如何掌握五行
The Emperor's mystics taught him mastery over the five elements,
火 水 土 木 金
fire, water, earth, wood and metal.
他的力量无限壮大
His power seemed without limit.
成为了万人的主宰
He was master of millions,
然而就如最低贱的贱民一样  他渐渐变老
but like the lowliest peasant, he could not stop growing old.
朕  要寻找永生之道
I have too much to do for one lifetime.
他要击败他的最后一个敌人  死亡
NARRATOR... He needed to defeat his last enemy, death itself.
直到有一天  他听到传闻
One day, news came of a powerful witch
一个道姑知道长生不老的秘方
who was rumoured to know the secret to eternal life.
于是他命令自己的老朋友 忠实的部下明将军去找这个道姑
He ordered General Ming, his oldest friend and trusted ally, to find her.
这个道姑名叫紫苑
The witch was named Zi Yuan,
她跟明将军所想的不一样
and she was nothing like the General expected.
参见陛下…
Your Majesty...
平身
Rise up.
皇上所求  奴婢不知如何解答…
I do not possess the secret of immortality, my Lord...
…却知答案藏于何处
...but I know where to find it.
将军…
General...
此女
No man is to touch her.
非朕莫属
She is mine.
在西面边陲有一座吐鲁番寺庙
NARRATOR... On the western border stood the Monastery of Turfan.
这是古代藏书最多的地方
There was housed the greatest library in the ancient world,
紫苑相信不老的秘方就藏于此
and Zi Yuan was sure the secret to eternal life was here.
此乃开锁之物
This is a key.
这是一块失传已久的甲骨
NARRATOR... It was the long lost oracle bones,
记载了古时的所有秘密
a collection of all the mystical secrets of the ancient world.
皇帝所要的答案就在里面 其中还隐藏了其他超凡的秘密
The Emperor's answer was here along with other magic beyond imagining.
朕甚悦
You have served me well.
汝何所求  朕皆赐之
I will grant you anything you desire.
愿与郭明共渡余生
I want to spend my life with General Ming.
准
Of course.
念
Read.
她用皇帝听不懂的梵语念诵着
NARRATOR... She cast the spell in Sanskrit,
这是一种古老语言
an ancient language that the Emperor did not understand.
此语朕虽不解
I feel your spell working.
然觉于气  流行于筋络之间
I am now immortal.
朕要你见一个人
Come, I want to show you something.
郭郎
为朕的皇后  可饶其不死
Become my queen and I will let him live.
从其令  卿之命为重
Do what he says! Save yourself!
你必食言
You will never keep your word.
正是
You are right.
与郭明地府相见吧
Now, join General Ming in hell.
你竟敢施法于朕
你对朕做了什么
What did you do to me?
咒汝及汝之徒!
I cursed you and your army.
快护驾!
Surround the Palace!
皇上出事了!
The Emperor is in trouble!
咒语绝对不能解除
NARRATOR... The curse must never be lifted,
否则皇帝会重返人间  奴役众人
or the Emperor will rise again to enslave all of mankind.
那天来临时  也将是世界末日
On that dark day, there will be nothing and no one to save us.
木乃伊 龙帝之墓
你可以跑  但你无处可藏
You can run, but you can't hide.
一点钟方向
One o'clock.
英国牛津郡  1946年
OXFORDSHIRE, ENGLAND
十点钟  一点钟  十点钟  一…
Ten o'clock, one o'clock. Ten o'clock, one...
这就是成人该做的?
And this is something for grown men to do?
快点
Come on.
靠这了
Bite on this.
伊芙  我回来了!
Evy, I'm home!
奥康纳夫人去读书会了  先生 她会回来吃晚饭
Mrs O'Connell is at her book reading, sir. She'll be home for dinner.
哦  好的  非常好  正好我钓了鱼
Oh, right. Well, that's great, 'cause we're having fish.
你没想到我会钓到  是吧?
You didn't think I'd catch anything, did you?
我对你绝对有信心  先生
I had the utmost confidence, sir.
你的脖子上有个鱼钩  先生 要我帮你去拿钢丝钳吗?
JAMESON: There's a hook in your neck, sir. Shall I fetch the wire cutters?
里克…退后!跟着我! 快!快!快!快!
RICK... Fall back! Follow me! Move! Move! Move! Move!
"最后安全登上飞艇  木乃伊终于被打败了
EVELYN..."Now safely aboard the airship with the mummy finally vanquished,
伦敦
LONDON
"达什将斯嘉丽拥入怀中
"Dash swept Scarlet into his arms.
‘哦  天哪  斯嘉丽  我以为失去你了’ ‘曾有一时  确实如此‘
"'Oh, God, Scarlet, I thought I'd lost you.' 'For a moment there, you did.'
"沐浴在金色阳光下
"Bathed in rays of golden sunlight,
"我们的英雄们激情拥吻庆祝着重逢
"our heroes sealed their reunion with a kiss of timeless passion,
"他们的爱比以往更深更真"
"their love deeper and truer than ever."
奥康纳夫人  我们都非常好奇
Mrs O'Connell, we're all dying to know,
斯嘉丽·奥凯弗这个角色的原形真的是你吗?
is the Scarlet O'Keefe character really based on you?
老实说  她和我是截然不同的人
Honestly, I can say she's a completely different person.
- 还有问题吗? - 奥康纳夫人…
- Any more questions? - WO Mrs O'Connell...
奥康纳夫人  你如今的生活与战前一样精彩吗?
Mrs O'Connell, is your life today as exciting as it was before the war?
但愿我的生活能和那时一样精彩
I wish my life were that exciting now.
这个系列还会出新书吗?
Will there be another book in the series?
会有大团圆结局吗?
WOMAN 2: Do you believe in happy endings?
这样不是很幸福吗?
Isn't this blissful?
一起在家吃饭
Dinner at home.
- 每天晚上 - 每天晚上
- Every night. - Every night.
- 为了退休干杯 - 希望永远这么幸福
- Here's to retirement. - May we stay this happy forever.
还是没有亚历克斯的信 上个月我给他寄了3封
Still no letter from Alex. I've sent him three in the last month.
是嘛  你还想怎么样?
Yeah, well, what do you expect?
他只有被赶出学校或是缺钱时
The only time we ever hear from that kid
才会寄信回来
is when he's getting kicked out of college or he needs more money.
我相信他正埋头于学习中
I'm sure he's just buried in his studies.
- 不说了  你的读书会怎么样? - 哦  很好  谢谢
- So, how did your book reading go? - Oh, fine. Thank you.
不过他们问起我 "什么时候会出新的木乃伊探险记"
Until they asked me, "When will there be another Mummy adventure?"
你确实向出版社保证过会出第三本
Yeah, but you did promise the publisher a third book.
我知道
I know.
可我整晚盯着白纸  脑子一片空白
But I spend my nights staring at a blank page, completely blocked.
那我们不吃了  上楼去
We could skip dinner, and I could
我会试着启发你
attempt to inspire you upstairs.
哦  你真好  亲爱的
Oh, that's so sweet of you, darling.
可我还是想坐在打字机前  直到灵感涌现
But I'm going to sit at that typewriter until something exciting comes out.
谢谢
Thank you.
鲑鱼  太棒了
Trout. How lovely!
很高兴你找到个不用枪的爱好
I'm so happy you found a hobby that doesn't involve guns.
中国宁夏省
NINGXIA PROVINCE, CHINA
一定能找到
Don't worry, we'll find the entrance today.
李彤  午饭?
Li Tung, what's for lunch?
热的汤
Noodle soup.
哦  好好
Very good.
很好  威尔逊回来了
ALEX: Good. Wilson's back.
你晚了好几天  教授
You're a couple days late, Professor.
我还以为你碰上抢劫了
I was beginning to think you'd run into bandits.
哦  我亲爱的朋友  谢谢你的关心
Oh, my dear fellow, thank you for the concern.
- 你渴吗? - 哦  是的
- Are you thirsty? - Oh, yes, please.
- 给你 - 谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
知道吗  看见你站在那
You know, when I saw you standing up there,
我还以为是你父亲
I thought I was looking at your father.
不愧是里克·奥康纳的儿子
You really are Rick O'Connell's son.
是啊  真希望从今以后 人们会称呼他亚历克斯·奥康纳的父亲
Yeah, well, hopefully after today, he'll be known as Alex O'Connell's father.
多有力的脸啊!
What a powerful face!
当我告诉博物馆的同事  你发现了兵马俑时
When I told my colleagues at the museum that you had discovered the Colossus,
他们非常震惊
they were thrilled.
- 呃  但是… - 我知道
- Yes, however... - I know.
什么时候我能进那个墓穴?
When am I gonna get in that tomb?
别为那些事烦心了
Don't let the buggers get you down.
是你发现了本布里奇的日记
It was you that discovered the Bembridge journal,
有了它  你很快会找到龙帝
and with it, you'll discover the Emperor.
- 我对你绝对有信心  亚历克斯 - 谢谢你  教授
- I have complete faith in you, Alex. - Thank you, Professor.
谢谢你相信我
Thanks for believing in me.
找到了!找到了!找到了!
We found it! We found the door!
讨厌的木乃伊
Bad Mummy.
是啊
Yeah.
可憎的木乃伊?
Vile Mummy?
不  受诅咒的木乃伊!
No. Cursed Mummy!
神秘的木乃伊
Mysterious Mummy.
邪恶的木乃伊
Malignant Mummy.
受死吧!
Prepare to die!
拿命来!
Take that!
里克!
Rick!
亲爱的  你在哪?
Darling, where are you?
我等着灵感涌现呢
I'm ready to be inspired.
还记得那次木乃伊把我捆住吗?
Do you remember the time the mummy had me tied down?
然后你来救我  切断了…
And you came to save me and you cut...
不!你扯断了绳子
No! You tore open the ropes is what you did,
就在他插入…
just as he was about to plunge his...
哦  见鬼
Oh, rats.
小心!
Watch out!
- 龙帝不欢迎客人 - 是啊
- Emperor didn't want any houseguests. - Yeah.
注意!不要走散了
Stay together.
科林·本布里奇爵士
Sir Colin Bembridge.
哦  啊…
Oh, gee...
70年前他来到这个墓穴
He went searching for this tomb 70 years ago.
他这样子应该是个警告
They left him like this as a warning.
很不幸  这并不是那个能让我们出名的死人
Unfortunately, this is not the dead man that's gonna make us famous.
继续走
Let's keep moving.
看啊  亚历克斯
Look at it, Alex.
看啊!
Look at it!
楚旺!
Chu Wah!
救命啊
- 楚旺 - 不  不  不要  不要  不要
- Chu Wah. - No, no, don't, don't, don't.
亚历克斯  亚历克斯  他们死了!走
Alex, Alex, they're dead! Come on.
那里很危险  你比任何人都清楚
This kind of danger goes with the territory. You know that better than anyone.
亚历克斯!
Alex!
- 嗯? - 没事
- Yes? - Okay.
- 是吗? - 是的
- Yes? - Yeah.
好的  好小子  很好  哦  天哪
All right, good chap. Okay. Good chap. Oh, Jesus.
所有的士兵都面向这点
All the warriors are facing in to this point,
- 就像在等待龙帝的命令 - 那么  他又在哪?
- as if awaiting an order from the Emperor. - Well, then, where is he?
听着  你不会以为是某些凶暴的盗墓者
Listen, you don't think some bloody grave robber's
攻击了我们把战利品拿走了吧?
beaten us to the prize, do you?
不  他还在这
No, he's still here.
看  这是风水罗盘
You see, this is a feng shui compass.
是啊  现在  这…
Okay. Now. This...
看  这是真正的北方
Okay, this is true north,
但风水罗盘却指向相反方向
but the feng shui compass is set in the opposite direction.
- 是啊  我们得调整一下 - 对
- All right, we need to realign it. - All right.
- 好吧  我们来 - 好的
- All right, here we go. - All right.
亚历克斯!亚历克斯  回话!
Alex! Alex, speak to me!
你还好吧?
Are you all right?
- 亚历克斯! - 我没事
- Alex! - I'm fine.
告诉我  怎么找到龙帝?
Tell me, have we found the Emperor?
亚历克斯!
Alex!
这是什么?
What is it?
这是自图坦卡门法老墓以来的唯一最大发现!
It's only the greatest find since King Tut!
"若他醒来  将是世界末日"
"If he is awakened, all mortals should despair."
肯定是他!
It's definitely him!
连他的妃子都得陪葬
Even had his concubines buried alive with him.
自私的混蛋
Selfish bastard.
嗨  威尔逊教授  你不下来看看吗?
Hey, Professor Wilson, you want to come down and take a look?
还是你激动地连话都说不了?
Or are you so overwhelmed you can't talk?
威尔逊!
Wilson!
走吧  教授  还有很多事要做
Let's go, Professor. We've got a lot of work to do.
好吧
WILSON: All right.
首先  谨代表
FRY: First of all, I'd just like to say
外交部感谢你们在战时所做的贡献
that the Foreign Office appreciates all that you did during the war.
不过派我来是为了交给你们最后一个任务
But I've been sent to offer you one last assignment.
恐怕我们已经从谍报游戏中退休了 不是吗  亲爱的?
I'm afraid we've retired from the espionage game, haven't we, dear?
是的  我们已经…我们再也不做了 我们退休了
Yeah, we've... We don't do that any more. We're finished.
- 没错 - 完全结束了
- EVELYN: Not at all. - Completely done.
不过我好奇问问  这次任务是什么?
But just out of curiosity, what is the mission anyway?
我们要你们把这个送到上海
We need you to courier this to Shanghai.
- 好漂亮的冰片 - 这是香格里拉之眼
- Nice piece of ice. - It's the Eye of Shangri-La.
传说它能指引通向永生泉之路
If you believe the legend, it points the way to the Pool of Eternal Life.
1940年从中国被盗出
It was smuggled out of China in 1940.
现在政府想要把它归还给上海博物馆
Now, the government would like to return it to the Shanghai Museum
以示对中国人民的友好诚意
as a sign of good faith to the Chinese people.
考虑到你们在这方面的经验 自然就想到了你们
And with your expertise in the field, we naturally thought of you.
哦  这真是我们的荣幸
Oh, we'd be so flattered.
但里克和我在战后互相许诺
But Rick and I, we made a promise to each other after the war
我们会安顿下来
that we would settle down.
- 是的  我们做到了  不是吗?我们… - 我明白
- That's right, yeah, we did, didn't we? We... - I see.
不过我得承认我有点失望
Well, I must admit I am a little disappointed.
战后的中国很危险
Postwar China is very dangerous.
有很多派别
There are a lot of factions that would love
会插足香格里拉之眼
to get their hands on the Eye of Shangri-La.
有可能香格里拉之眼会永远消失
In lesser hands, the Eye could be lost forever.
我们不能让这种事发生  不是吗?
We couldn't let that happen, could we?
是啊  这对世界来说太糟了
No, that could be bad for the world.
- 世界…太可怕了 - 是啊
- The world... Terrible. - Yeah.
你知道  她有个哥哥住在上海
You know, she has a brother who lives in Shanghai.
- 乔纳森! - 是的
- Jonathan! - Yes.
他经营着一家夜总会  我没记错的话
He owns a nightclub, if I'm not mistaken.
我们一直想去看看他  我们可以…
We have been meaning to visit. We could...
- 我们应该…顺便去看他  给他个惊喜
- We should... ...drop in and surprise him.
- 问候一下 - 为什么不呢?
- Say hello. - Why not?
这是否表示 我们能指望你们的最后一次帮忙?
Does this mean we can count on you one last time?
是的
Yes.
中国上海
SHANGHAI, CHINA
1947年春节
CHINESE NEW YEAR, 1947
干杯
There we are.
敬你一杯  公主
Here's to you, Princess.
为了伊姆贺特普  愿天下太平! (第一座金字塔的建筑师与设计者)
And Imhotep. May the bugger actually stay dead.
丁当
Ding-dong.
嘿  能请我喝杯吗?
Hi, can you buy a drink for me?
失陪一下  亚历克斯!亚历克斯!你又来了
Excuse me. Alex! Alex! You're back again.
过来  亚历克斯  请你喝一杯
Come here, Alex. Let me get you a drink.
给这小子来杯温和点的  哈?探险家
Smooth special for the pup, huh? The explorer.
来两杯
Make that two.
抱歉  乔叔叔  但那女人搭讪了我
Sorry, Uncle Jon, but I got a better offer.
不  不  亚历克斯  不  听我说 我怎么能…过来
JONATHAN: No, no, Alex. No, look. Listen, how can I... Come here.
用考古学的话来说
To put it in archaeological terms,
那是一个埋了许多法老王的墓穴
that's a tomb in which many pharaohs have lain.
现在  听着  听着  为我考虑下  好吗?
Now, listen, listen, just think about me for a moment, all right?
你的发现几天后就会公诸于世
Your discovery will go public in a few days
而你的父母肯定会知道的
and your parents are sure to find out.
对于你的辍学  他们不会高兴的 而且…
They're not gonna be happy you've dropped out of school. And...
放松点  乔叔叔?好吗? 我在这  而他们在很远的地方
Will you relax, Uncle Jon? Okay? I'm here. They're a long way away.
- 亚历克斯… - 我走了  好吗?
- Alex... - Excuse me, okay?
我还要去挖掘
I have some excavation to do.
乔纳森!
Jonathan!
你们来中国了!伊芙  里克
You're in China! Evy. Rick.
你们在…这真是…我甚至没有…
What are you... It's so... I didn't even...
哥哥  见到你真是太好了
Brother, how lovely to see you.
我不知道他在这!
I had no idea he was here!
- 谁在这? - 谁?
- Who was here? - Who?
每次都这样!
This happens every time!
酒吧里的每个人!
Every man in the bar!
- 爸爸? - 亚历克斯?
- Dad? - Alex!
- 我不知道该拿你怎么办! - 他还是个孩子!
I don't know what to do with you! WO He's just a boy!
- 10分钟内我不能离开这房间! - 我不能…走开!去死!
- I can't leave the room for 10 minutes! - I didn't... Go away! Go to hell!
- 我受够了! - 我们去找帅哥吧!
-  I'm sick of it! - Let's go get lover-boy!
我想杀了你  小子!
I'm gonna kill you, kid!
别妄想了  那是我的孩子
Not so fast, that's my kid.
- 疯狗马奎尔? - 跳飞奥康纳
- Mad Dog Maguire? - Ricochet O'Connell.
- 嘿  嘿 - 你在这干嘛?
- Hey, hey. - EVELYN: What are you doing here?
亚历克斯!甜心!你还好吧?
Alex! Sweetheart! Are you all right?
只是家庭聚会而已
Just a little family get-together, folks.
来吧  我们继续狂欢  音乐!
Come on, let's get back to having a good time. Music!
有多久了?
How long has it been?
1923年  埃及  法国对外志愿军
Egypt, '23. French Foreign Legion.
这家伙可随地降落飞机  你…
This guy could land a plane on anything, you...
- 你为什么在这? - 跳飞  他居然敢泡我的女人
- Why are you here? - Ricochet, he had his hands all over me girl.
现在  不管是不是你儿子 我都要教训他!
Now, son or no son, I gotta give him a beating!
- 让开  爸爸 - 坐下
- Get out of the way, Dad. - Sit down.
我更希望你能教他点更有用的…
Now as much as I'd really like you to teach him a valuable lesson...
他的妈妈会很伤心  非常伤心
His mother would be upset! Very upset.
你得好好解释下  年轻人
You have a lot of explaining to do, young man.
我有了妻子和孩子
I got a wife now, and a kid.
情况有点不同了  相信你能明白
Things are a little bit different, I'm sure you understand.
- 是的 - 我向你道歉
- Yeah. - Let me make it up to you.
在这看到你我们很惊讶 就是这样
We're just surprised to see you here. That's all.
谁来负责赔偿?
JONATHAN: Who's gonna pay for all this damage?
没事吧?
All right?
我才来了5分钟
I'm not here five minutes,
就帮你收拾烂摊子
and I'm already pulling your fanny out of the fire.
你必须回学校去
You're going back to college.
你觉得可能吗  爸爸?
How'd you think this was gonna work, Dad?
你们俩突然出现  到底要干什么?
You two show up, tell me what to do?
不  我们一家人应该坐下好好谈谈
No. But we should sit down and discuss this like a family.
请原谅  妈妈  但我们不像一家人很久了
No offence, Mom, but we haven't been a family in a long time.
嘿  别扭头就跑  亚历克斯!
Hey, don't you turn your back on me. Alex!
亚历克斯  只是…亚历克斯  过来
Alex, just... Alex, come here.
你能…
Can you...
不要那样看着我
Don't look at me like that.
- 都是你的错! - 我的错?
- It's all your fault! - My fault?
你老是宠着他
You're the one that's always smothering him.
你连不帮他擦鼻子五分钟都做不到
You couldn't leave him alone for five minutes without wiping his nose.
你从来都不关心他的生活
Perhaps I was overcompensating for the fact
所以我才过度补偿他
that you never took an interest in his life.
他的生活是我的头等大事
His life was my top priority.
多少次我给他收拾烂摊子?
How many times did I save that kid from breaking his neck?
一点温暖和鼓励就够了
A little warmth and encouragement would have been nice.
我是他的父亲  这是不能改变的
I'm his father. It's implied.
我们一生都在寻找奇珍异宝
We've spent our entire lives searching for priceless artefacts,
而对我们最珍贵的东西
and the one thing that's most precious to us,
我们却失去了
we've lost.
我们不能让亚历克斯变成某个陌生人
We can't let Alex become some stranger
而照片却挂在我们的壁炉架上
in pictures on our mantle.
- 我们不能让那发生 - 不  我们不能
- We can't let that happen. - No, we can't.
我们该如何弥补?
How are we gonna fix this?
我们必须齐心协力
We need to do it together.
中国西部  准军事哨所
PARAMILITARY OUTPOST WESTERN CHINA
奥康纳一家人已经到上海了
The O'Connells are in Shanghai.
他们拿到神眼了吗?
Do they have the Eye of Shangri-La?
是的  我们的线人已经证实这件事了
Our spy says they do.
好
Good.
召集军队!
Assemble the troops!
是
Yes sir.
弟兄们!
Soldiers!
我们所做的训练和牺牲…
Soon all our training and sacrifice...
很快就可以得到丰盛的成果
will bear great fruit.
重振皇威是我多年的夙愿
It is my dream to raise our Emperor from his tomb.
平定天下非吾皇莫属
Only He can bring order out of this chaos.
今晚…
Soldiers...
我们的圣战蓄势待发!
tonight our great battle begins!
知道吗  坐黄包车都比这快
You know, this might have been faster if we took a rickshaw.
这是中国的春节
It's Chinese New Year.
你不正是喜欢这个国家吗?
Don't you just love this country?
这有着那么多特别的节日  还一定要喝酒
They have so many extra little holidays, and drinking is mandatory.
难以相信我们要去看你的第一大发现
I can't believe we get to see your first big discovery.
太兴奋了
It's so exciting.
经昨晚后  我还以为你们根本不想看呢
Well, after last night, I'm surprised you want to see it at all.
听着  一个小时后我来接你们
JONATHAN: Listen, I'll pick you up in about an hour.
你不来?
EVELYN: You're not coming?
不  不  我这辈子看够木乃伊了
JONATHAN: No, no, I've seen enough mummies to last a lifetime.
就是他
There he is.
哦  亲爱的  多震惊啊
Oh, my darling, very impressive.
你打算什么时候打开石棺?
When do you get to open the sarcophagus?
等官方的正式文书下来吧
ALEX: Well, after the official red tape has been cut.
你们俩不知道"安息"这两字吗?
Do the words "rest in peace" mean anything to you two?
妈妈  你何不在这多留几天呢?
So, Mom, why don't you stick around for the next few days,
我们可以一起打开它
and we can open it together?
太好了  谢谢
I would like that very much, thanks.
亚历克斯  为什么不去告诉威尔逊教授
Alex, why don't you go and tell Professor Wilson
我们在这  你知道…
that we're here. You know...
没问题  太棒了
No problem. Great.
我离开的时候可不要把上面那家伙叫醒
Just don't wake the big guy up while I'm gone.
嗨  亚历克斯
Hey, Alex.
你知道  这一切真的是一个大发现
You know, this is all really, really big stuff.
随你怎么说  爸爸
Whatever you say, Dad.
怎么了?
What?
今晚你真是光彩夺目
You just have a certain glow about you this evening
我很久没见过了
I haven't seen in a long time.
我想这多亏了木乃伊
I guess mummies bring out the best in me.
在开罗失之交臂?抱歉打扰了
Take a wrong turn at Cairo? Sorry to interrupt.
- 罗杰 - 罗杰·威尔逊教授
- Roger. - Professor Roger Wilson.
里克
Rick.
知道吗  当亚历克斯告诉我你也参与时
You know, when Alex told me that you had gone legit,
别提我有多惊讶
I just couldn't believe my ears.
呃  我只是以保护的名义挖掘墓穴而已  伊芙琳
Well, now I just pillage tombs in the name of preservation. Evelyn.
- 恭喜你的最新发现 - 这都是亚历克斯的功劳
- Congratulations on your latest discovery. - Alex deserves all the credit.
真是个厉害的孩子  我把他当自己儿子一样
He's one hell of a kid. He's like the son I never had.
我们就只有他这么一个孩子
And he's the only one we've got,
所以下次你派他去实地考察时
so the next time you send him on one of your field trips,
请先知会我们一声
you give us the heads-up first.
好的  好的  当然
Yes, yes, of course.
我想你们拿了我们的东西
And now, I believe you have something that belongs to us.
是什么?
What's that?
哦  是说这个?
Oh, you mean this?
抱歉…
I'm sorry...
给  拿着
There, go ahead.
你的  罗杰
All yours, Rog.
我就知道能信任你们
I knew I could rely on you two.
恐怕你们的任务还没完成  奥康纳先生和夫人
I'm afraid your work is not done yet, Mr and Mrs O'Connell.
我来给你们介绍个朋友  杨将军
I'd like to introduce you to a friend of mine. General Yang.
罗杰!
Roger!
就是他资助亚历克斯这次的挖掘 我们是一伙的
Well, he is the man who financed Alex's dig. We're in this together.
并肩战友  将军
Cheek by jowl. General.
搜他身
Search him.
不  神眼属于中国人民  你们不能这么做
No. The Eye belongs to the Chinese people. You can't do this.
罗杰你个小人  你收了多少…
So, Rog, you snake, how much did...
是阴阳?……给你钱?
Is it Yin and Yang? ...pay you?
为了确保是你们俩送来神眼
Enough to pull strings at the Foreign Office,
我们在外交部可下了一番功夫  转过去
make sure that it was you two who delivered the Eye. Turn around.
神眼里含有永生泉的泉水
The Eye contains the elixir from the Pool of Eternal Life.
我要你打开它  奥康纳夫人
I need you to open it, Mrs O'Connell.
不
No.
你要用它来唤醒龙帝  对不对?
You're going to use it to wake the Emperor, aren't you?
还有他的兵马俑军队 这是我们的目的
And his Terracotta Army. At least, that's the general idea.
唤醒一支木乃伊军队真是疯了 听着  杨…
Raising an army of mummies is insane. Listen, Yang...
老实点!给我老实点
Easy! Go easy.
打开石棺  快!
Time to open the sarcophagus. Move!
念铭文!快!
Read the inscription! Now!
中国古文不是我的强项
Ancient Chinese isn't my forte.
看来需要点刺激  威尔逊!
Here's some encouragement. Wilson!
我念!
I'll do it!
不  伊芙  不要念! 他们最后还是会杀了我
No, Evy, don't do it! They're just gonna kill me, anyway.
铭文上说  只有拥有纯洁之心的人的一滴血
The inscription says that only a drop of blood
才能打开神眼
from a person of pure heart can open the Eye.
你的丈夫说得对
Your husband was right.
不!
No!
只有心灵纯洁才会为所爱之人牺牲自己
Only the pure of heart would sacrifice themselves for the one they love.
打开
Open it.
上次见面后你就没找过我
You never called after our last date.
没时间开玩笑  亚历克斯
I don't have time for games, Alex.
你知道我的名字  而我却不知道你的
You know my name, but I don't know yours.
我叫琳
It's Lin.
你是来向我解释要杀我的原因吗?
You want to explain to me why you tried to kill me?
我们可以这么做
We could do that.
或者我们可以去救你的父母
Or we could save your parents.
威尔逊  你个狗娘养的!
Wilson, you son of a bitch!
- 继续  奥康纳 - 好吧
- Get on with it, O'Connell. - All right.
一旦龙帝接触到这个  就会复活重新统治天下
Once this touches him, the Emperor will rise to rule again.
杀了他
Finish him off.
亚历克斯  求你了!不要  那是…
Alex, please! Don't. That's...
不要  不要  不要  求你了
Don't, don't. Don't, please.
不  不要  亚历克斯  是我  求你了
No, don't, Alex, it's me. Please.
不是他  这是个太监!这是圈套!
It's not him. This is a eunuch! It's a decoy!
龙帝到底在哪?
Where the hell's the Emperor?
呆着!
Stay!
又来了
Here we go again.
皇上  我是来保护你的
I live to serve you, my Lord.
我能帮你获得永生
I can help you become immortal.
如果你说谎  随时烧死你
If you are lying, you will burn.
等等!等等!等我下!我和你一起走!等等  等等…
Wait! Wait! You wait for me! I'm coming with you! Wait, wait...
小心!
Watch out!
我们得快去阻止那个木乃伊!
RICK: We got to put this mummy down fast!
时间越长  他们越强大!
The longer we wait, the stronger they get!
打开大门!打开大门!
Open the gate! Open the gate!
侬想死啊?
是  是  是  我知道  抱歉  朋友 有个木乃伊被放出来了
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I know. Sorry, pal. There's a mummy on the loose.
- 你来开车? - 为什么不呢?
- You wanna drive? - Why not?
天哪  我爱上一个开卡车的女人
God, I love a woman who can drive a truck.
嘿  朋友  非常抱歉  但你知道吗? 新年快乐!
Hey, pal, I'm really sorry, but you know what? Happy New Year!
快开车  宝贝!
Hit it, honey!
不!让开!
No! Move over!
什么?不!
What? No!
不!
No!
- 什么? - 乔纳森  上车!
- What? - Jonathan, get in the back!
抱歉毁了你的车!
Sorry about the Rolls!
你们真像木乃伊磁铁!
You guys are like mummy magnets!
- 你得转过来! - 好的
- We have to turn you around! - Okay.
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 嘿  我们可以用这个! - 给我!
- Hey, we could use this! - Give me that!
- 哦  是啊  主意真不错 - 真大啊!
- Oh, yeah, that's a better idea. - RICK: Size counts!
别逗了!他们要跑远了!
Stop mucking about! They're getting away!
开好车!
Just drive!
- 瞄准龙帝! - 瞄准龙帝?
RICK: Aim for the Emperor! JONATHAN: Aim for the Emperor?
- 快点上  乔纳森! - 我在点啊!
- Light it up, Jonathan! - I'm trying!
开火!
Fire!
打中了吗?
Did we get him?
- 着火了! - 什么  还来?
- Fire! - What, again?
- 你屁股着火了! - 我的屁股?
- Your ass is on fire! - My ass?
- 不要动! - 里克  我屁股着火了!
- Hold still! - Rick, my ass is on fire!
- 快  拍我的… - 弄熄它!
- Well, spank my... - I'm putting it out!
- 帮我弄熄  里克! - 叫你不要动!
- Put me out, Rick! - Just hold still!
拍我的屁股!拍我的屁股!
Spank my ass! Spank my ass!
好吧  我来了!
All right, here I come!
把手给我!
LIN: Give me your hand!
快点!
Come on!
小心!
Watch out!
伊芙  你去哪?
RICK: Evy, where are you going?
- 抄近路! - 伊芙!
- Taking a short cut! - Evy!
- 跟你说了这是近路! - 是啊!
- I told you it was a short cut! - Right!
换他追我们了!
Now he's chasing us!
快!
Hurry!
把手给我  给  你会需要这些
Give me your hand. Here, you're gonna need these.
- 不用等我 - 你去哪?
- Don't wait up for me. - Where are you going?
出去!
Out!
- 里克呢? - 你觉得他会去哪?
- Where's Rick? - Where do you think?
该死!
Damn it!
你是我的!
You're mine!
- 把手给我  上马来! - 回去  爸爸!
- Give me your hand and get on this horse! - Get back, Dad!
亚历山大·鲁珀特·奥康纳 立即给我坐到马后面去
Alexander Rupert O'Connell, you get on the back of this horse this instant!
让开!让开!哦  天哪!
Get out of the way! Get out of the way! Oh, God!
伊芙!
JONATHAN: Evy!
我们得回去帮里克!
We've got to go back and help Rick!
里克!忘了里克!他们来了!
JONATHAN: Rick! Forget Rick! Here they come!
我去追龙帝
I'll go after the Emperor.
相信我  对付木乃伊  我更在行
Trust me. I've got a little more experience with mummies.
我拿着唯一可以杀死他的武器
And I have the only weapon that can kill him.
好吧  我掩护你  上!
Okay. I'll cover you. Let's go!
琳!
ALEX: Lin!
- 我以为你死了! - 他打偏了
- I thought you were dead! - He missed.
小心!
LIN: Look out!
谢谢  里克  你能去付钱吗?
Thanks, Rick. Could you get the cab?
我像带钱包的人吗?
Does it look like I have a wallet?
知道吗  我差点就杀了龙帝
You know, I would have killed the Emperor
要不是你们俩暴露了我的行踪
if you two hadn't blown my cover.
一切皆在我掌控之中
I had everything under control.
哦  是嘛  我们就是这么想的
Oh, yeah, that's exactly what we were thinking.
是啊  动作真快  你又复活了一个木乃伊
Yeah, well, good going, you raised another mummy.
而这混蛋还有超能力
And this bugger's got superpowers.
他能控制火  水  金  天晓得还有什么
ALEX: He's got control over fire, water, metal and who knows what else.
你却把他挖了出来
And you dug him up anyway.
是的  你不会想把这个也怪到我头上吧  爸爸?
Yeah, well, you're not gonna pin this one on me, okay, Dad?
- 是我吗? - 哦  住口  你们两个
- RICK: Am I? - Oh, stop it, you two.
不是谁的错  是威尔逊利用了我们
No one's to blame here. Wilson manipulated all of us.
确实如此
Yeah, that's true.
我为我父母向你道歉
I apologise for my parents.
不过我觉得我们合作地还不错
But I thought we worked really well together.
除了没杀成龙帝
Except we failed.
抱歉  我们还没互相介绍过
I'm sorry, we haven't been properly introduced.
- 你到底是谁? - 我叫琳
- Who are you exactly? - My name is Lin.
几个世纪以来我的家族一直看守着龙帝的墓穴
My family has watched over the Emperor's tomb for centuries.
只有用这个刺穿龙帝的心脏才能杀死他
The Emperor cannot be killed unless he is stabbed through the heart with this.
我母亲很久以前就在这上面下了咒语
My mother put a curse on it long ago.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
过来  简短开下家庭会议  亚历克斯
Well, a quick family meeting, Alex.
- 坐 - 下
- Sit. - Down.
你对这女孩了解多少?
What do you really know about this girl?
不是很了解
Well, not much,
但经过今晚她的帮助 我愿意相信她
but after her help tonight, I'm willing to go on a little faith.
- 相信 - 没时间了
- Faith. - Time is running out.
你真的不懂什么叫私人空间吗?
You don't really believe in the concept of personal space, do you?
若龙帝到达香格里拉  喝下永生泉水
If the Emperor reaches Shangri-La and drinks from the Pool of Eternal Life,
他会唤醒他的军队  到时大家都完了
he will raise his army and no one will be safe.
就像我想永远年轻英俊一样
Much as I'd like to stay this boyishly handsome forever,
香格里拉只是个传说
Shangri-La is a crock.
是啊  以前你也是这么说木乃伊的  乔
Yeah, but that's what you used to say about mummies, too, Jon.
- 真会开脱啊 - 你说对了
- You did pretty well off it. - Good point.
香格里拉的入口位于喜马拉雅山的高处山口
The Gateway to Shangri-La lies in a mountain pass high in the Himalayas.
远处是一座金塔
Beyond it is a golden tower.
一旦钻石放到顶部  就会指出通向香格里拉的道路
Once the diamond is placed at the top, it will point the way to Shangri-La.
杨将军还拿着钻石
Yang still has the diamond,
他和龙帝一定会去那
and that's where he and the Emperor will go.
她说得对
She's right.
关于神眼的所有传说都提到了入口
All the legends of the Eye mention the Gateway.
这姑娘不错  亚历克斯  她知道所有事情
I like her, Alex. She knows what's what.
我们相信你了  你能带我们去那吗?
Now, just say that we were to believe you, could you guide us there?
好的  我去过一次  我记得路
Yes. I have been there once. I remember the way.
喜马拉雅山  我们需要一架飞机
Himalayas. We're going to need a plane.
我只知道疯狗能做到
Well, I know just the Mad Dog for the job.
任何有自尊的飞行员都会在谷底降落
MAGUIRE: Well, any self-respecting pilot would land on the valley floor,
不过我可没什么自尊可言
but I don't have any self-respect,
所以我会在半山腰把你们放下
so I'll put you down halfway up the mountain.
那会对我们有利
That should give us a good advantage.
当然  但我不能保证我们所有人都能活着
MAGUIRE: Of course, I can't guarantee any of us will live.
好的!
Great!
我该告诉你们系好安全带的 可我太穷了买不起
I'd tell you to fasten your seatbelts, but I was too cheap to buy any!
- 我干嘛笑? - 到了!
- Why am I laughing? - Here we go!
疯狗  疯狗! 慢点  慢点  慢点!
RICK: Mad Dog, Mad Dog! Ease up, ease up, ease up!
哦  天哪!
JONATHAN: Oh, God!
马奎尔!
JONATHAN: Maguire!
快啊  朋友!
Come on, man!
疯狗!
Mad Dog!
停下!不  不!大家不要动
RICK: Brake! No, no! Nobody move.
不要动  大家都不要动!
Nobody move, nobody move!
那是什么恶心味道?
What is that God-awful smell?
牦牛吐的
The yak yakked.
恭迎皇上来到20世纪
Welcome to the modern world, my Lord.
唤朕何为?
Why did you raise me?
我们需要陛下带领我们重振声威
I love this land. Only you can lead us back to greatness.
尔等何求?
What is in it for you?
当阵将军  侍奉主人
I want to serve as your general.
上一个将军…
The last general I trusted...
背叛朕
betrayed me.
臣不会犯此错误
I will not make that mistake.
这泥之身无力唤醒大军…
I cannot escape this curse until I am immortal...
将军
General.
臣明白
I understand, my Lord.
故臣已获陛下长生秘诀
We need to find the Pool of Eternal Life.
此物能明示长生之道
This will point the way.
Can't you see it's Mr McGuire 没看到是麦奎尔先生嘛
Can't you see it's Mr McGuire
come to court your sister Kate 来向你妹妹凯特求爱
come to court your sister Kate
你知道他有一家农场  一个小小的…
You know very well he owns the farm a wee bit out...
德耳塔-探戈-阿尔法  呼叫跳飞 回答  跳飞
MAGUIRE O VER RADIO... Delta-Tango-Alpha to Ricochet. Come in, Ricochet.
德耳塔-探戈-阿尔法  我是跳飞  说吧  疯狗
Delta-Tango-Alpha, this is Ricochet. Go ahead, Mad Dog.
嗯  记得你要我留意的那个叫杨的家伙吗?
Yeah, you know that Yang fellow you told me to keep me eye out for?
他刚刚出现了
He's just shown up.
跳飞明白  谢了  疯狗
Ricochet out. Thanks, Mad Dog.
该我们了  大伙!出发!
That's us, people! Let's go!
- 乔纳森  醒醒! - 什么…
- Jonathan, wake up! - What...
坚持下去!
Hold the line!
很好  我们已经走了过半的路程
Good, we're a little more than halfway.
我们在…今晚我们在那过夜
We're gonna... We're gonna camp up there for the night.
琳说  如果我们在黎明出发 我们就能在中午前到达入口
ALEX: Lin says if we leave at first light, we'll reach the Gateway by noon.
她有没有说她是如何知道这么多入口的事的?
Did she happen to mention how she knows so much about the Gateway?
没  没有  她有点神秘兮兮的
No, not really. Kind of mysterious.
显然她把你迷倒了
She's certainly managed to enchant you.
得了  亚历克斯  你喜欢上她了
Come on, Alex. You obviously like her.
妈妈  山上空气稀薄  你也头脑发昏了
Mom, the thin mountain air, clearly messing with your head.
无论她藏着什么秘密
Whatever secret she's hiding,
我只是不想看到你受伤
I just don't want to see you get hurt.
我很感激  但是  你知道
I appreciate that, but, you know,
我对异性也有很多经验了
I've had my fair share of experience with the opposite sex.
真的?
Really?
那有多少次经验了呢?
How many experiences are we talking about?
不想知道答案就不该问
Well, you shouldn't ask questions you don't want to know the answer to
知道吗  妈妈?
okay, Mom?
好吧
Right.
嘿  妈妈
Hey, Mom.
很抱歉因木乃伊被唤醒的事而责怪你们
I'm sorry I blamed you guys for raising the Emperor.
有什么好笑的?
What's so funny?
我妈觉得我们之间有什么
My mother is under the impression there's something between us.
我希望不是什么浪漫的事
I hope nothing romantic.
是啊  我跟她说没什么机会
Yeah, well, I told her there was no chance of that.
我们完全是不一样的人  你和我  明白吗?
We're complete opposites, you and me, right?
你守护墓穴  而我是盗墓的 你喜欢古代刀剑  我喜欢枪支
You guard tombs. I raid them. You like ancient knives. I'm into guns.
这些都是不易改变的差异
Those are some pretty insurmountable odds.
- 完全如此 - 很好
- Absolutely. - Well, good.
既然我们开诚布公了 我们就能专心消灭龙帝了
Now that we've cleared that up, we can focus on taking down the Emperor.
完全同意
I agree totally.
还有  你不是我喜欢的类型
Besides, you're not my type.
当然了  你不会喜欢一个能将你背摔的女人
Of course not. You don't like a woman who can knock you on your backside.
应该说"踢我的屁股"
The expression is "kick my ass."
到目前为止你还没做过
And for the record, you didn't.
哎  我真是不容易啊  知道吗
Yeah, it's not easy being me, you know.
同样地  我想你也不容易吧
Then again, I don't suppose it's easy being you,
不是吗  杰拉尔丁  老姑娘?
is it, Geraldine, old girl?
如果我遇上像你这样的女孩  杰拉尔丁…
If I'd met a girl like you, Geraldine...
勤快  话不多
You know, hard-working, you don't say much,
毛比较多  但我不介意
you're a little bit hairy, but I don't mind that.
在那!我们找到了!
There it is! We found it!
香格里拉的入口!
The Gateway of Shangri-La!
走  姑娘!走!你自由了
JONATHAN: Go, girl! Go! You're free!
走吧  杰拉尔丁  自由自在地活着
Go, Geraldine! Live free!
你在干什么?抢劫武器?
What did you do now? Rob an armoury?
你见过瓦尔特P38吗?
Have you ever seen a Walther P38?
比调停者逊多了
Looks pretty anaemic compared to the Peacekeeper.
不是大小的问题  爸爸  而是火力的问题
Well, it's not about size, Dad. It's about stamina.
你要火力?
You want power?
给你汤普森冲锋枪  50发一弹鼓
I give you the Thompson submachine gun. Fifty rounds a drum.
- 25弹匣 - 是不错  爸爸
- Twenty-five a mag. - Tommy's good, Dad,
但击发装置老卡壳
but the cocking mechanism always jams.
来  看看俄罗斯产的PPS个人攻击武器
Here. Check out the Russian PPS Personal Assault Weapon.
这才是需要的
Now, this is the future right here.
靠经验才能成功  光靠火力是没用的
You know, it's experience that wins the day. It's not all about firepower.
小伙子们!我可以…
Boys! If I may...
我们有什么计划对付龙帝吗?
Do we have a plan for the Emperor?
有啊  我们会又快又狠地将他打飞
Yeah. We're gonna hit him high, hard and fast
然后再把他当成明代花瓶一样打碎
and smash him like a Ming vase.
- 如果那没用呢? - 我们还有B计划
- And if that doesn't work? - We go to plan B.
B计划!你爬上去  然后炸了那座金塔
Plan B! You go upstairs, you blow up that gold tower thing.
- 你点火  我们把他炸上天! - 我?
- You light it up. We blow the guy sky high! - Me?
- 你!什么? - 爸爸?
- You! What? - Dad?
如果我们没炸死  也会被雪崩压死
So if the explosion doesn't kill us, the avalanche will.
- 你有更好的主意? - 是的  有啊
- You got a better idea? - Yeah. I do.
我的想法是  用远程消音来复枪伏击他
I say we ambush him with long-range rifles and silencers.
远程  很不错的主意
Long-range, that's a better idea.
是啊  我们可以慢慢靠近  爸爸
Yeah, we can get in close, Dad.
- 听起来不错 - 然后了结他
- JONATHAN: Much better idea. - And then we can finish him off
- 用琳的匕首 - 抱歉
- with Lin's dagger. - Look, I'm sorry,
我不太相信你女朋友的神奇匕首
I just don't put much faith in your girlfriend's magic dagger.
- 好吧  爸爸  她不是我女朋友 - 你现在这么说了
- Okay, Dad, she is not my girlfriend. - You say that now,
- 但我还是不相信她 - 我信
- but I still don't trust her. - Well, I do.
- 你该相信我的判断  知道吗? - 听着  孩子
- So you should trust my judgement, okay? - Look, kid,
我干掉的木乃伊比你多
I've put down more mummies in my time than you.
你只干掉过一个  爸爸
You put down one mummy, Dad.
是啊  同一个木乃伊两次!
Yeah. Same mummy twice!
把绿线递给我  好吗?
EVELYN: Hand me the green wire, will you, please?
你有把握吗?
Are you sure you know what you are doing?
当然  我做过一百次了
Of course. I've done this a hundred times.
如果龙帝把神眼放在那上面 那什么都完了
If the Emperor places the Eye up there, all will be lost.
扫清障碍
Clear a path to the Golden Tower.
让朕见识一下  你是何等的良将
Prove yourself to me.
火箭炮
给他们来个热烈的奥康纳式欢迎!
Let's give a warm O'Connell welcome!
开火!
Fire!
- 火箭炮! - 开火!
Bazooka!
退后!
RICK: Fall back!
亚历克斯!跟我来!
Alex! Follow me!
快点!
我们得干掉那些火箭炮!
We gotta take out those bazookas!
走!
Go!
- 全跟我来 - 退后!
Fall back!
快!快!快!快!
Move! Move! Move! Move!
实行B计划!炸了塔!
Time to go to plan B! Blow up the tower!
嘿  我对B计划不怎么放心!
Hey, I'm actually a little bit concerned about plan B!
我们直接进行C计划吧?
Couldn't we go straight to plan C?
快去引爆它!我掩护你!
Just make it go bang! I'll cover you!
快
Come on.
好吧  我们走  走  走!快  快!
All right, let's go, go, go! Come on, come on!
快  哦  小心点
Come on. Oh, be good.
你们右边!
Set up a crossfire!
快! 右边小心
Move it!
最后一弹匣!
EVELYN: My last round!
耶缇  索特  快来啊! 耶缇  索特  快来啊!
- 喜马拉雅雪人? - 西藏人管他们叫耶缇!
- Abominable snowmen? - The Tibetans call them yeti!
求你们了!我需要你们的帮助!
Please! I need your help!
那些士兵是魔鬼!
These soldiers are evil!
她会说耶缇语?
She speaks Yeti?
开火!把他们干掉!
Shoot! Kill them!
为什么老是我来做这种扭转乾坤的事!
Why do I always have to save the day?
我讨厌得听从小孩的!
I hate it when the kid's right!
对付另一个家伙!
Get the other guy!
谢谢!
Thanks!
敌人!
Trouble!
想慢慢地死还是痛快地死
You can die slow or you can die fast.
丑八怪!
快!快!快!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
耶!我搞定了!
Yeah! I did it!
哦  妈呀  我搞定了!该撤退了
Oh, Mother, I did it! Time for a retreat, I think.
我们是一伙的!我是成员之一!
I'm on your team! I'm a team player!
"我为人人  人人为我"类似的!
"One for all and all for me" kind of thing!
炸药  那些炸药!我们得离开这!
The dynamite, all this dynamite! We should get out of here!
退后!退后!
Back off! Back off!
跑!
LIN: Run!
我恨木乃伊!他们从不公平对决!
I hate mummies! They never play fair!
爸爸!爸爸  你要干什么?
Dad! Dad, what are you doing?
这里!这里!来啊!这里!
Over here! Over here! Come on! Over here!
哦  不!
Oh, no!
里克!
Rick!
香格里拉
Shangri-La.
那是钻石
That's a diamond.
我喜欢那么大颗钻石!
I could use a diamond like that.
爸爸!
Dad!
哦  坚持  坚持住  爸爸
Okay, hold it. Hold on there, Dad.
不会有事的  求你了  求求你 求求你  坚持住  好不好  爸爸?
All right, please, please, please put pressure on it, okay, Dad?
没事的  没事的  再糟糕的都经历过了
RICK: It's all right, it's all right. We've been in tougher scrapes than this.
雪崩!
Avalanche!
- 帮我!帮帮我! - 琳!
- Help! Help me! - Lin!
求求你们!帮帮我!
Please! Help me!
耶!
Yes!
我拿到了!我还活着!
I've got it! And I'm still alive!
帮我  求求你们  谁来帮帮我!
ALEX:  Help me, please. Somebody help me!
- 我们在这里!在这里! - 亚历克斯?
- We're over here! Over here! - Alex?
- 妈妈  妈妈  我们在下面 - 亚历克斯
- ALEX: Mom, Mom, we're down here! - Alex?
我们在这里!
We're over here!
哦  天哪
Oh, God.
我们得马上带他到香格里拉! 这是我们的最后机会
We've got to take him to Shangri-La now! It's our only chance.
到了!
We made it!
那池子
The Pool.
母亲
Mother.
小宝贝
My sweet daughter.
求求你…求求你
I beg you...
我父亲
My father is dying.
需要帮忙
They are my friends.
哦  求求你
Oh, please.
走
go
谢谢
Thank you.
他需要休息  带他去我的房间
He must rest. We'll take him to my chamber.
你去哪  将军?命运等着我们
Where are you going, General? Our destiny awaits.
不是所有人的妹夫都能死里逃生的
Well, it's not everyone that gets their brother-in-law back from the dead.
我一生80年中给我那么十天就好了
Yeah, give me my four score years and ten any day.
这是香格里拉?
Is this Shangri-La?
我可以住这  机会多多
I could live here. Lots of opportunity.
一个娱乐场
A casino.
让你参与我的复仇计划是一个错误
I was wrong to involve you in my revenge.
不  母亲
No, mother.
您让我干什么都行
I would do anything for you.
他在休息了  谢谢
ALEX: He's resting well. Thank you.
你们是怎么卷进来的?
How'd you get involved in all this?
皇帝杀了我唯一爱过的男人  琳的父亲
The Emperor murdered the only man I ever loved, Lin's father.
要不是耶缇发现了我  把我带到这池子
I would have died, too, by his hand,
我应该也被他杀了
if the yeti had not found me and brought me to this pool.
等等  这是如何发生的?
Hang on a second. How did this all happen?
这都是公元前的事了
This was before Christ.
你守卫这个墓穴多久了?
How long were you guarding his tomb?
超过两千年
Over 2,000 years.
不能让皇帝靠近这个池子
The Emperor must never be allowed to reach the Pool,
否则他就有力量召集他的军队了
or he will have the power to raise his army.
一旦他变成不死之身
And once he becomes immortal,
他将成为前所未有的邪恶生物
he can transform himself into the most hideous creatures ever seen.
我先去守护入口
I will take the first watch at the entrance.
知道嘛  我不介意和老女人约会
You know, I have no problem dating an older woman.
恐怕我们不能在一起
I'm afraid we can't be together.
等等  什么?为什么?
Wait. What? Why?
因为我是不死之身
Because I'm going to live forever.
我不要看着你死
I don't want to watch you die.
那又怎样?就因为这个?
So what? That's it?
你想就这样算了  就这样永生吗?
You're just gonna sit on the sidelines for eternity?
母亲为父亲伤心了好几个世纪
My mother has mourned my father for centuries.
我不知道自己是否能承受
I don't know if my heart can bear it.
人无法在哀伤中过一生
People can live an entire lifetime in one look.
我的父母就是这样过来的
I watch my parents do it every day.
亚历克斯?
JONATHAN: Alex?
你父亲醒了  上来!
Your father's awake. Get up here!
嗨
Hello.
如果这是天堂  那还真是不错
If this is heaven, it looks pretty good so far.
真高兴看到某些永恒的东西
Nice to see some things never change.
对他宽容点  他吓坏了
Go easy on him. He feels terrible.
我看到你躺在那里时  爸爸…
When I saw you lying there, Dad...
我从没这么害怕过
I've never been so scared in my life.
我也是
Well, that makes two of us.
我的意思是  你不会死的  明白吗?
I mean, you know, you're not supposed to die, you know?
你可是跳飞·奥康纳  不是吗?
You're Ricochet O'Connell, right?
你被打被摔
You get beat up, you get tossed around,
但最后你仍是站在那
but, well, you're always standing there in the end.
我从没想过没有你的世界
I never really thought of the world without you.
亚历克斯
Alex,
实际上
the truth is,
我只是想…
I'm just trying to...
我只是…
I'm just...
我想当一个好丈夫
I'm trying to be a good husband.
我想当一个好父亲
I'm trying to be a good parent.
而事实是  最近我做错了  而且…
And the truth is, I've been dropping the ball lately, and...
不是的  你知道  我不是一个好儿子  不是吗?
No, you know, I haven't been the world's greatest son, you know?
不  不  那都是遗传自你妈妈
No, no, that's 'cause you get it from her side of the family.
来
Come here.
我的儿子
My boys.
你看来好累了  你得休息
You look tired, you should rest.
我留下来
I'll stay.
命运快到最后的决战时刻了
Fate is about to deal its final hand.
要是我们想击败皇帝…
If we are to defeat the Emperor...
我得要求你再做出一次牺牲
I must ask for one more sacrifice.
什么都行  母亲
Anything, mother.
献出你的永生
Your immortality.
哦  不!他的力量完全恢复了
Oh, no! His powers have been fully restored!
行动吧
Time to go.
郭明的女儿
General Ming's daughter.
她是我的了
Your child will be mine.
他是不死之身
He is immortal.
嘿!你这三头怪物  狗娘养的!
Hey! You three-headed shape-shifting son of a bitch!
琳!
Lin!
亚历克斯!
LIN: Alex!
Alex!
他带她回墓穴召集军队去了!
He's taking her back to his tomb to raise his army!
- 有没有更快的方法赶到那? - 耶缇  他们能帮上忙
- Is there a faster way down from here? - The yeti. They'll help.
可他已经飞上天了  太晚了!
But he's already in the air. It'll be too late!
疯狗飞得可比这三头蜥蜴快多了!我们走
Mad Dog can outfly a three-headed lizard any day of the week! Let's go.
左边!9点钟方向!
MAGUIRE: Portside! Nine o'clock!
里克?我是不是该戒酒了?
Rick? Should I quit drinking?
乔纳森呼叫里克
O VER RADIO... Jonathan to Rick.
如果你们想把他打回墓穴  你们最好快点!
You'd better get a move on if you're gonna beat him to the tomb!
是啊  是啊
Yeah, yeah,
你尽快带增援回来
just get back here as fast as you can with the reinforcements.
不要看风景了!
No sightseeing!
给你  爸爸
Here, Dad.
- 给我? - 是啊
- Is that for me? - Yeah.
不错
Nice.
只要兵马俑军队没越过长城  我们还可以击败他们
The Terracotta Army is not indestructible until it crosses the Great Wall.
太好了  到底我们该如何阻止他们呢?
That's comforting. How exactly are we supposed to fend them off?
皇帝建造长城时
When the Emperor built the Wall,
把他的敌人都埋在城墙下
he buried his enemies underneath it
并诅咒他们的灵魂永世不得超生
and cursed their souls to hold it up for eternity.
大部分是被打败的士兵  我会召唤他们再次战斗
Most of them were conquered soldiers. I will call them to battle once again.
打开祭坛  召唤军队  这计划不错  走吧
Unlock an altar, raise an army. That sounds like a plan. Let's go.
抓住了
Grab her.
- 看紧她 - 跟我来
Guard her with your life.
亚历克斯?
Alex?
- 他人呢? - 你觉得呢?
- Where'd he go? - Where do you think?
醒来!
AWAKE!
尔等醒于今…
Today you awake to a world...
止世上混乱腐败
in the grip of chaos and corruption.
打开通往过去的入口
Open the gates of the past
释放受害者的灵魂
and free the souls of the wrongfully damned.
必恢复法制…
I will restore order...
朕  必须夺回天下
I will retake what is mine.
绝自由于患
I will crush any idea of freedom.
以祖先和正义之名
In the name of the ancestors and the righteous,
献上我与女儿的永生
I sacrifice my immortality and that of my daughter
来让你们复活!
so that you may rise this day!
朕召尔等
I will slaughter without mercy.
威望广施正义于天下
I will conquer without compassion.
尔等随朕
I will now lead you past the Great Wall.
跨越长城  长生不老
Once you cross, you will be indestructible.
熄灭被压迫者对暴君及其追随者的怒火!
Bring down the wrath of the oppressed on this Emperor and all who follow him!
攻占城池!
I raised you for one purpose...
大开杀戒  毫不留情!
to enforce my will on the entire world!
皇上万岁!
Long live the Emperor!
我召唤你们  成千上万的冤魂
I call upon the hundreds and the thousands
把握此刻  赢得胜利
that you may rise up and seize this moment to take your victory,
以正义之名  报仇雪恨
to take your justice and to take your revenge!
紫苑
Zi Yuan.
明将军!
It's General Ming!
跟随明将军!
Follow General Ming!
备战!备战!
Prepare for battle!
这些是…他们是不死的好人  对吧?
These are... They're good undead guys, right?
哦  不  不  不!
Oh, no, no, no!
紫苑!紫苑!紫苑派我们来的!
Zi Yuan! Zi Yuan! Zi Yuan sent us!
- 亲爱的  我不觉得他会说英语 - 我们站在紫苑这边!
- Darling, I don't think he speaks English. - RICK: We're with Zi Yuan!
紫苑?
Zi Yuan?
是的
Right.
冲啊
Let's go.
战斗!
To battle!
自由!自由!自由!
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!
换箭阵!
Archers form up!
来了!
Incoming!
- 嘿!那是我最喜欢的蓝衬衫 - 我一直不喜欢那件衬衫
- Hey! That's my favourite blue shirt. - I've always hated that shirt.
啊  对不起啊  对不起对不起 你头在这  你头在这
灭郭明!
Death to General Ming!
冲啊!
Charge!
欢迎来到20世纪!
Welcome to the 20th century!
向右翼进攻
We can't let them cross the wall!
你已非不死之身
You are no longer immortal.
亲爱的!退回高地!
Honey! Fall back to higher ground!
我真的很讨厌木乃伊!
I really hate mummies!
我也是!
It seems the feeling's mutual!
闭嘴  粘土小子  砍你的头!
Shut up, clay boy! Fore!
快跑!
Run!
- 接住! - 拿到了!
- Catch! - Got it!
下次我说"比这个更糟的都经历过" 就是指这次!
Next time I say, "We've been in tougher scrapes than this," I mean this!
去死  你们这群木乃伊混蛋!都去死!
Die, you mummy bastards! Die!
没必要说脏话
There is no call for bad language!
乔纳森真能把握入场时机
Jonathan certainly knows how to make an entrance!
有遗憾吗  亲爱的?
Any regrets, darling?
没  永远不会
None. Not ever.
- 你们没事吧? - 当然  没问题
- You okay? - Yeah, sure, no problem.
完全在我们的控制之中
We had it completely under control.
这家伙怎么那么多花招?
This guy ever run out of tricks?
不!
No!
母亲!不!
Mother! No!
母亲!
Mother!
母亲!母亲!
Mother! Mother!
刺穿他的心脏
Pierce through his heart.
你得活着  战斗下去
You must live and fight on.
她说刺穿心脏
She said through the heart.
刺穿心脏  我们走
Through the heart. Let's go.
快上车!
Get in!
奥康纳他们要去刺杀皇上了
The O'Connells are going to stop the Emperor!
爸爸  有计划了吗?
So, Dad, what's the plan?
声东击西!
Divide and conquer!
不用攻击  是不是太简单了?
No offence, but isn't that a little short on detail?
- 十二点方向下面! - 抓紧!
- Twelve o'clock low! - Hang on!
记得我们说好的!
Remember our deal!
一切结束后  请我们喝酒!
When this is over, my men get to drink for free!
整个酒吧拿去都没问题!
You can have the whole damn bar for all I care!
我可不想呆在中国!
I'm getting the hell out of China.
当初是我挖你出来的…
I dug you up...
现在我要赶你回去
and I'm gonna put you down.
亚历克斯?亚历克斯!
Alex? Alex!
放开!
Let go!
不!
Never!
把戏玩够了!你的骄傲呢?
RICK: Enough tricks! Where's your honour?
像个男人一样打一场!
Fight like a man!
声东
Divide
击西
and conquer.
去地府当你的皇帝吧
Now you can rule in hell.
皇帝死了
The Emperor is dead.
皇帝死了!
The Emperor is dead!
- 晚上好  姑娘们  你们好漂亮 - 晚上好  马奎尔先生
- Evening, girls. You're looking well. - WO Good evening, Mr Maguire.
- 真是个不错的夜晚 - 就一个老女人来说  你跳得很好了
- It's a fine night to be me. - You dance great for an old lady.
有人叫我放开自己
Someone told me to stop living on the sidelines.
- 听起来是个聪明的家伙 - 是的
- Well, he sounds like a smart guy. - He is.
我猜达什和斯嘉丽又有了新的冒险?
So I guess Dash and Scarlet have their next adventure?
都经历过了  干嘛还写?
Why write about it when you can live it?
打败木乃伊时发生不少浪漫故事
There's something incredibly romantic about vanquishing the undead.
特别是和你在一起的那些更浪漫
Even more romantic doing it with you.
- 吻我 - 不用问我第二次
- Kiss me. - Don't have to ask me twice.
- 要我帮你拿包吗  先生? - 不  不  不用
- Can I get your bag, sir? - No, no, no.
别碰  不要碰
Don't touch it, don't touch it.
你要去哪  卡纳汉先生?
Where are you off to, Mr Carnahan?
没有木乃伊的地方
Someplace where they don't have mummies.
- 快点!我要赶飞机 - 是  先生
- Step on it! I've got a plane to catch. - DRIVER: Yes, sir.
耶  再见  再见  上海
Yeah. Ciao, ciao, Shanghai.
秘鲁  我来了
Peru, here I come.
不久之后  秘鲁发现了木乃伊
Soon after, mummies were found in Peru.